

# Guangsheng Bao

PhD Candidate Natural Language Processing Westlake University and Zhejiang University Advisor: Prof. Yue Zhang ▶ baoguangsheng@westlake.edu.cn • GitHub Profile

### Introduction

I am Guangsheng Bao, a Ph.D. candidate jointly enrolled at Westlake University and Zhejiang University, under the guidance of Prof. Yue Zhang. My primary research interests center on Natural Language Generation, encompassing areas such as Large Language Models, Neural Machine Translation, and Text Summarization. My scholarly contributions include the publication of various research papers in reputable venues such as ACL, AAAI, EMNLP, and TASLP. I have also actively participated in the academic community by serving as a reviewer for conferences like ACL, EMNLP, ICML, NIPS, TACL, COLING, and others, and as an Area Chair for COLING 2022.

Prior to my pursuit of scientific research, I gained industry experience with positions at Alibaba, where I worked on customer service robot systems, and at Microsoft (China), where I contributed to the development of Cortana.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### • Conference proceedings:

2020 - present

Guangsheng Bao, Yanbin Zhao, Zhiyang Teng, Linyi Yang, Yue Zhang. 2023. Fast-DetectGPT: Efficient Zero-Shot Detection of Machine-Generated Text via Conditional Probability Curvature. (under review)

Guangsheng Bao, Zebin Ou, Yue Zhang. 2023. GEMINI: Controlling The Sentence-Level Summary Style in Abstractive Text Summarization. In Proceedings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP2023), Singapore, December.

Guangsheng Bao, Zhiyang Teng, Hao Zhou, Jianhao Yan, Yue Zhang. 2023. Non-Autoregressive Document-Level Machine Translation. In Findings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP2023 Findings), Singapore, December.

Guangsheng Bao, Zhiyang Teng, and Yue Zhang. 2023. Target-Side Augmentation for Document-Level Machine Translation. In Proceedings of the 61th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2023). Toronto, Canada from July 9th to July 14th, 2023.

Guangsheng Bao, Zhiyang Teng, and Yue Zhang. 2023. Token-Level Fitting Issues of Seq2seq Models. In Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP (RepL4NLP@ACL2023). Guangsheng Bao, Yue Zhang, Zhiyang Teng, Boxing Chen and Weihua Luo. 2021. G-Transformer for Document-Level Machine Translation. In Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2021), Online, July.

Guangsheng Bao and Yue Zhang. 2021. Contextualized Rewriting for Text Summarization. In Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI2021), Online, February. Dandan Huang, Leyang Cui, Sen Yang, Guangsheng Bao, Kun Wang, Jun Xie and Yue Zhang. 2020. What Have We Achieved on Text Summarization? In Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP2020), Online, October.

• Journal articles: 2023 - present

Guangsheng Bao, Yue Zhang. 2023. A General Contextualized Rewriting Framework for Text Summarization. In IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing (TASLP2023).

#### **EDUCATION**

· Westlake University, China

## · University of Science and Technology of China

MEng, software engineering

## · HeFei University of Technology, China

BEng, computer science

Sep.2000 - Jun.2004

Sep.2005 - Jan.2008

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### • Text Intelligence Lab, Westlake University

Jun.2019 - Aug.2022

Research Assistant

Hangzhou

- Research: text summarization, neural machine translation, and coreference resolution.
- Published two first-author long papers during the period, including AAAI 2021 and ACL 2021 (Oral).

## • Institute of Data Science and Technologies, Alibaba

Mar.2015 - Jun.2017

Algorithm Expert

Hangzhou

- Research & development: online customer service robot system and hotline customer service robot system.
- Investigated the latest Question Answering techniques and built them into the solution for customer service.

### • Information Platform Group, Microsoft (China)

Spr.2013 - Feb.2015

Software Development Engineer

Suzhou

- Research & development: Natural Language Understanding engine for Cortana.
- Led several virtual teams working on training/testing/deployment tools and producing NLU models for languages such as Spanish, French, Italian, etc.

## • Exchange Server group, Microsoft (China)

Jan.2008 - Mar.2013

Software Development Engineer

Beijing

- Software design & development: Manageability for Exchange server.
- Participated in two whole release cycles of Exchange Server 2010 and Office 365.

## OTHER EXPERIENCE

### • Travel & Self-study in Edinburgh

Jul.2017 - Jun.2018

Visitor

Edinburgh

- I accompanied my wife on a visiting scholarship at the University of Edinburgh during the period. I took the chance to explore my interests and studied some philosophy and cognitive science theories.
- I explored the cognitive science theories and tried to build a whole picture of it, studying several topics such as sensation, perception, imagination, conception, and language.
- I found my passion for these topics, so I decided to pursue a research opportunity on natural language processing, in which area I already have some basic knowledge.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Languages: English (IELTS 7.0), Chinese (native speaker).

**Developer Tools**: Python, C++.

Soft Skills: Cross-team collaboration, Team leading.

**Areas of Interest**: AI, Robotics, Neural Science, Psychology.